# JAY QUIGLEY

9

M

.

in

C

Berkeley, Calif.

quigley.james.g @gmail.com jayquigley.net

in/jamesgquigley

850.274.1846

#### SUMMARY

Tenacious, driven, detail-oriented, effective altruist. Rigorous, analytical, interdisciplinary researcher who habitually explores multiple alternatives deeply. Seasoned communicator with significant teaching and writing experience. Resourceful and highly organized. Affable teammate dedicated to framing feedback positively. Driven by a fervent commitment to producing a high altruistic impact.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

AVANT

Chicago, Illinois

**Junior Software Engineer** 

FEB. - JUL. 2016

- Self-taught ReactJS & EcmaScript 2015 to build a Monthly Net Income Calculator, saving Avant an estimated \$60,000 annually in call center specialist productivity
- Pioneered a scalable Ruby class architecture for call center specialist task reminders

#### FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY

Tallahassee, Florida

## **Graduate Instructor & Teaching Assistant**

2007-2015

- Honed superb communication and critical thinking skills in speech and writing, on topics as diverse as formal logic, practical ethics, and political philosophy
- Gained experience explaining difficult concepts simply, giving constructive feedback, and inspiring students to think critically
- Taught 3 university courses; served as TA for an additional 15 courses

#### ANIMAL CHARITY EVALUATORS

Remote

**General Intern** 

APR. - AUG. 2014

- Drafted the organization's first development and fundraising plan, after researching and consulting with numerous effective altruist and nonprofit leaders about their fundraising strategies
- Piloted a study on the effectiveness of 'pay per view' video outreach promoting vegan food choices
- Assembled seventeen letters of intent for grant applications and one full grant application

#### **SELECTED PAPERS & PRESENTATIONS**

TEDxFSU: "Ending the suffering of billions: overcoming speciesism": over 9,000 views as of Sep. 2016.

Scholarly publication: "Moral Psychology and the Unity of Morality". Utilitas 27 (2):119-146.

**Doctoral dissertation**: Caring and the Apprehension of Value.

Blog: 21<sup>st</sup> Century Altruism.

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

## SENTIENCE POLITICS

Remote

Volunteer

SEP. 2016 - present

 Working on a foundational document for the Swiss animal rights political think-and-do-tank's expansion to the United States.

## STUDENTS FOR ENDING POVERTY (STEP)

Tallahassee, Florida

#### Co-founder and Vice President

MAR. 2013 - MAY 2015

 Seeded and guided organization devoted to learning about and raising money to combat global extreme poverty. Affiliated with The Life You Can Save.

### FSU UNDERGRADUATE ETHICS BOWL TEAM

Tallahassee, Florida

Coach

2009 - 2012

Motivated and advised undergraduate students in intercollegiate debate-style competitions

## **EDUCATION**

DEV BOOTCAMP, Chicago, II., 19-week intensive web development course, 2015 FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY, Tallahassee, Fla., **Ph.D., Philosophy**, 2015 FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY, Tallahassee, Fla., **M.A., Philosophy**, 2009 TRUMAN STATE UNIVERSITY, Kirksville, Mo., **BA, Philosophy and Religion**, 2007